[Music]
w
hello and welcome to the ask abijit Show
episode 174 I hope you're all doing very
well I hope you're all doing great um
it's been almost 3 years since I've been
doing this uh this particular thing ask
abijit and I really appreciate you all
watching I really appreciate that so
let's see who all is there on the live
chat today with us I can see Arian Zin
sub
shanu an Girish wag kov VI Singh Alpha
tagat triban anul sinari miir karney Mr
X gaming SG Costo nanjan Sami Jan T
divine nature ishan Mani tripati rsr
fighter Mao Perez geopolitical dub hello
aluminati Creek feminist Slayer Neo
Karan naat hello Jam LKR 799 jippy
Phoenix tagat Karan Akil mu swasti GA
nanan badage threat
Ripper uh Sunil seal anur Singh vitri
Martinez Manan takur divine nature
knowledge Camp Madura class drove s
Deepak mat Rambo
6789 sh sha Arnav Arnav Ry Amisha Mishra
hello rajat Duhan Neo dianu prian sud
adiya nitish har Pratap Singh Junior
Journey Shashi Kiran Pavan B Austin
Joseph hello prian rala ainash Universal
Pro shaitan Singh CP
Varma uh lots and lots and lots of other
people ramita Sinha assassins Fox
atish digpal Karan Karan tilak Sai Kumar
akit Demon Slayer prasa Jang
tapa and everybody else I won't be able
to as usual greet you all personally but
thank you so much for being on the live
stream and let's take some
questions what we talk about today
entirely depends on you all so let's
let's get it get it get it going please
ask me your questions and I will take as
many of them as possible over the over
the next two or so hours all right so
let's see this is by Dia Dia namaskaram
do you think all this racism on social
media and mainstream news towards
Indians is a propaganda that they're
using for this upcoming election yeah
interesting question if you go to social
media today okay if you go to Twitter or
or whatever I'm I'm not sure about
Instagram but if you go to Twitter where
essentially the entire world congregates
and has conversations you will see a
tremendous amount of racism right now
these days to towards Indians and this
is something that we have seen picking
up over the past year and a half maybe
two years it's increasing the volume
intensity is is is increasing the amount
of racism that you see towards Indians
on a daily basis the amount of racist
tweets or posts whatever you want to
call them the volume is increasing okay
and you've seen that from various parts
of the world typically from the Western
World okay and there's and whenever
something bad happens in India
it's going to be Amplified massively
everyone talks about it look at what's
wrong with India and so on and when even
worse things happen as they do all over
the world no one talks about that so
it's like certain things are uh you know
you're going to highlight and certain
things you will simply ignore depending
on where the the crime or whatever
occurs right so you've seen this and the
question is why is this happening why
are we seeing this uptick this
significant massive uptick in racism and
against Indians against Hindus and this
these anti-india posts
Etc what is causing this why are we
seeing so much of this in recent times
and there are a number of factors behind
this first of all I'm sure that there
still are lots of accounts on Twitter or
x what it's called these days that are
automated accounts that are accounts
created for propaganda purposes what
they call Bots I'm sure Elon Musk has
done his best to eradicate as many BS as
possible but at the end of the day this
is a platform that's owned by the US and
uh by the west and they can do certain
things and you know make make certain uh
certain
Impressions uh happen so one of the
possibilities is that there is a
concerted effort to malign in India and
this is not something that's organic but
it's more more of a geopolitical thing
okay because India is rising India is
rising the economic strength is rising
the technological advancement is rising
India has almost completely eradicated
extreme poverty not poverty but Extreme
poverty right and that's not me me
that's saying it it's the IMF and World
Bank and all that that have put out the
data right so there is this this
significant visible
demonstrable rise of India India has
become a significant geopolitical player
in the in in the Asia Pacific region in
the Indian Ocean region right it's it's
one of the like one could say the top
five powers in the world today whether
you believe it or not it is from the
perspective of hard power so if you look
at all of this India is rising and it's
making lots lots of existing Powers
really
uncomfortable so they are trying their
best to you know to to dampen the morale
of the Indian Nation because morale is a
thing morale creates momentum morale
creates positivity morale gives you
strength and power and stamina and all
that the higher your morale is depending
on how much you're winning and how much
you're doing well the better you'll
perform so one of the ways to dampen
moral is to put out this barrage of
anti-india tweets and posts and things
on social media so one of the components
could be the geopolitical component that
certain governments I mean if you
remember Edward Snowden and his
Revelations about prism it was very
clear that around 2010 around that time
the Americans had a very clear grasp of
what was happening on social media and
they could manipulate social media to
create to to create real world events
and to make things happen they could
Trend whatever they wanted in a certain
nation and India was one of the top
nations from which they were extracting
data okay so that was 20 roughly 2010
this is almost 15 years ago so imagine
the kind of capabilities they have
today and the US is is uh whether you
like it or not whether you believe it or
not is is it doesn't see India as as a
friend there are no friends obviously in
geopolitics but the US sees India as a
long-term competitor and possible threat
not today but 20 years down the line but
what happens 20 years down the line
depends on what happens today so they uh
they obviously plan for the for the long
term they plan for the future so that's
one of the issues so one of the
components could be geopolitical they
are creating this imp these these this
kind of impression on social media and
the other thing is that um Ordinary
People in the west they also are not
happy with the rise of
India right and I mean racism is a thing
every country has racism yeah I'm sure
India also has racism right for for good
reasons bad reasons right reasons wrong
reasons doesn't matter but there is the
a certain amount of this in every nation
and uh we know the history of the West
the past 500 years they have been
winning theyve been ruling the world
even today we are living under the so
called rules based world world order
which the West the Anglo-Saxons have
created the Anglo-Saxon world and when
there is a new nation that rises up and
a nation that they have failed to
destroy we are not a nation we are a
civilization we are a civilization State
we are the oldest continuously existing
civilization in the world we are the
oldest civilization that still practices
its own culture and worships its own
Gods and that is a from their
perspective not a good thing it's a loss
for them that they could not do to India
what they did to Greece what they did to
Rome what they did to let's say Persia
what they did to Africa they devastated
Africa no nobody in Africa practices
their own culture these
days what they have largely succeeded in
doing in in South Korea to some extent
in Japan so they have failed to do that
in India and so and then so there are
all these factors that are causing this
this tremendous outpouring of racism uh
on social media and also on mainstream
news like the is saying you'll see a lot
of these mainstream news stories you
have all these indices happiness index
democracy index yeah good fun uh so you
have all that in which they I mean if
you look at I the the so-called alleged
happiness index then India is lower than
Afghanistan Pakistan and Palestine in
the happiness index that's how unhappy
we Indians are I mean what a joke so
they do all this to dampen India's moral
to make Indians doubt themselves yeah
and to create a certain impression of
the world they want to maintain a
certain uh picking order in the world so
all this mainstream media is essentially
paid media it's all propaganda all media
is to some extent propaganda okay all
media has biases every individual has
biases I have biases obviously I'm the
first to say that I'm biased I Am pro
India I am biased towards India and
everything I say is going to be colored
with that bias I recognize that and I I
I embrace that okay I am very strongly
Pro India so everybody has biases but
the others are hypoc hypocritical in in
in the sense that they claim that they
are neutral no one's neutral the BBC
isn't neutral the CNN isn't neutral Fox
isn't neutral Twitter or X isn't neutral
Facebook isn't neutral nothing is
neutral with social media platforms or
mainstream media platforms and all that
even if you look at Indian mainstream
media every single Channel or or or
public ation or platform if you look at
the kind of coverage they do of various
events you will clearly see biases okay
and the biases you can understand the
root cause of the biases when you look
at the funding you know where the money
is coming in for each of these platforms
so that's how it goes okay so this is a
lot of this is propaganda for sure
anti-india propaganda there is this
concerted effort to dampen the moral of
Indians and make Indians feel that
they're not good enough they're in
inferior and all that and Indians
already have this inferiority complex
lots of them you know compared to I mean
lots of Indians feel that that
foreigners are better that white people
are superior somehow that Indians have
inferior genetics I mean look at the
questions I get on this channel look at
my old video clips and all that so many
of these questions I have fielded so
there is the genuine inferiority complex
that that is there among
Indians and so these all of this is is
is just a means to amplify that and to
perpetuate that so what I would say is
that disregard all this nonsense okay be
confident we're going to win I'm not
saying we're going to have to defeat
everyone we don't want to defeat anyone
winning means you rise to the fullest
extent of your potential that's all so
that's how we're going to win okay it's
going to take time but we're going to do
it and obviously there's the elections
that's going to come up I mean the
election dates were declared today I
believe today so obviously there's going
to be efforts to interfere in the
electoral process the Americans are p
Masters at that they have always been
claiming that Russia has been
interfering in their relations but they
are the ones who interfere everywhere
okay they have been talking about CA and
all that what business do they have
talking about CA it's none of their
business it's an internal matter of
India one of the first principles of the
global so-called rules-based World Order
is the principle of sovereignty and non
interference and they are the First
Nation to repeatedly disregard that rule
selectively so that's the deal all right
good question to start off with let's
take more
questions um let us see what else do we
have um Akil says when will the media
move out from India Pakistan to India
China and politics military wise foreign
policy tactics Etc I remember for the
longest time on on mainstream media we
had these so-called strategic Affairs
experts today they're all rebranded as
geopolitics experts okay before the year
2021 nobody used the term geopolitics in
India they were all strategic Affairs
experts and for them foreign policy
meant Pakistan international relations
meant Pakistan some of the biggest news
anchors in India when the prime minister
of India would go to the US the some of
these media channels I'm not naming
anybody by the way okay so some of these
media channels would go to the US okay
and they would interview various experts
in Washington DC and the first question
would be but what about Pakistan that so
it was the Indian media itself and the
Indian experts themselves that were
insistent on hyphenating India and
Pakistan together so that thankfully has
kind of broken today today the the Hyer
nation is between India and China the
competition that is quite visible is
between India and China so that's a good
move Pakistan has become too
insignificant I'm I'm not I wouldn't say
Pakistan has become ins insignificant
Pakistan is hasn't changed but India has
changed India has grown very rapidly and
very significantly over the past DEC
decade and today there's no comparison
between India and Pakistan the
pakistanis understand that we understand
that the world even the world has given
up on trying to hyphenate India and
Pakistan even the Americans have given
up on that now the hyphenation is India
China and please understand that India
currently is way way way weaker than
China China from the hard power
perspective is three to four times more
powerful than India not just from the
GDP perspective from a overall hard
power perspective how do I come up with
these figur stats figures data numbers
it's because uh I have calculated the
hard power scores of every single nation
and uh if you want to learn how to do
that check out my geopolitics course
Link in the description all right just a
very quick plug so I have calc and I'm
going to put out the index I'm going to
put
out this this coming week the chavda
index of hard power Global rankings I'm
going to put it out and so you you're
going to be able to see where each
Nation stands and what you will see is
going to be very surprising it's going
to surprise you and many of you may not
agree with that well that's okay see the
thing is we see power from a GDP
perspective well GDP isn't all there is
to power you may be the richest person
in your city but the smallest politician
can come and take away all your wealth
what matters is hard power in the
context of City politics Street power
you may be the wealthiest person in your
city but if you don't have the street
power which politicians have then
there's nothing you can do if the
politicians decide to take away your
wealth okay I'm talking about a
hypothetical City not any specific City
by the way all right so so the thing is
that India and China if you compare them
China is about three to three and a half
or maybe four times more powerful than
India right now but the situation is
fluid and the situation is changing the
Hyer Nation today is between India and
China so the media is slowly moving out
of this Pakistan Centric mindset the
shift has already happened and the
Indian media typically takes the lead
from the Western media from the from the
Americans typically so the Americans
themselves have kind of now given up on
hting India and Pakistan because it
makes no sense from from any perspective
from any angle okay so now the Indian
media is also following their lead so
that's what's happening and that's a
good thing but what we need is we need
proper China experts I mean anybody can
claim I'm a China expert anybody can
claim I'm a strategic Affairs expert or
geopolitics expert now the thing about
Pakistan Pakistan experts is that we
understand the language and the culture
language and the culture is is ours the
religion is is a foreign religion that's
fine but the language that the
pakistanis speak and the culture and the
mindset and everything we understand
completely we understand it thoroughly
okay so there can be lots of Pakistan
experts in India just because it doesn't
take too much of an effort to understand
Pakistan when it comes to China to be a
genuine China expert you need to
actually understand their language you
need to be able to speak the language
and read the language and do research
and and research the you know the study
the research papers that they come up
with and to understand what's really
going on in their mind so to be a
genuine China expert I mean today
anybody can claim any claim any kind of
expertise okay but to be a genuine China
expert which I am not because I don't
speak the language you have to be able
to speak the language read the
language and study do proper research of
of the of of the content that is
produced within China maybe on social
media maybe in their mainstream media
official media and and more importantly
what the military uh literature is what
the academic literature is you need to
be able able to study that and the
advantage the Chinese have is that they
aren't mentally colonized like Indians
they don't use English to do research
and to publish literature academic
literature they use their own language
mandering Chinese so to be a genuine
China expert you need to be able you
need to be fluent in mandering chines
otherwise you are not an expert I will
not consider you an expert
so I'm not an expert in China because I
simply don't speak the language I've
never taken the time to study it
probably I never will but whatever so
that's what India needs we need genuine
domain experts subject matter experts
and that's something we are lacking
right now but hopefully things
change
right goam vun says how should our
country promote Indian languages and
make make them the medium of instruction
and replace English it is something that
I have advocated for very long time
which is and lotss of people point out
that abijit you yourself speak in
English I know those people who pointed
out I I I would commend their powers of
observation brilliant powers of
observation I really applaud that the
reason I use English Today is because I
want to first of all connect with
everybody in India lots of people in
India have never bothered to learn Hindi
and I I'm not saying it's a good thing
or a bad thing okay and I want to reach
out to everybody and I want to reach out
to the external world as well okay
whatever I am saying over here whatever
I whatever content I create I want the
rest of the world also to understand it
right now whether we like it or not the
dominant language is English so let's
use the language of the colonizer to put
our perspective forward what needs to
happen it needs to happen through the
government of India okay and this the
moment the government of India tries to
Outlaw English there's going to be a
tremendous push back from all the you
know from all the from you know where
from The Usual Suspects they're going to
push back they going say that India
English is an Indian language there can
be no progress without English there can
be no science without English there can
be no technology without English all
that there can be no progress without
English well CH how did they progress
without English they don't use English
Japan doesn't use English Germany
Germany doesn't use English France
doesn't use English but the the but that
we are still far away from that there's
going to be a tremendous amount of push
back from our own mentally colonized
people many of them are good people they
don't even understand they don't realize
iiz how mentally colonized they are
there are lots of good people I know who
believe that English is a strength that
India has that we speak English I'm not
saying they are wrong or they are bad of
course they're wrong
but but you know you need to have self
resect and you need to why not make an
Indian language the dominant language in
the world why not why is it impossible
the the these these Anglo-Saxons from a
small island in the Atlantic could do it
they could make their language the
dominant language in the world why can't
a civilization of 1.4 1.5 billion people
make their language the dominant
language in the world so we have to
think big the government has to take
steps I think the government will not do
it in the next five years also but one
day a time will come when India is
secure enough mentally and confident
enough to take this forward it's going
to take time it's going to it's going to
require change of mindset among the
people see in in a democratic system
like India the government only does what
the people demand to not it any
government would be stupid I would say
to uh to take to take actions that that
are deeply unpopular among a large part
of of of subset of the of the population
so it's going to take time but
eventually when the when whatever
happens it should be like you need to
bring in an Indian language you cannot
have 17 Indian languages what you can
have is you can have one single
civilization language and then so that
could be the one medium of education and
the second could be your mother tongue a
two Lang language system today we have a
three or four language system English
and Hindi and your local state language
three languages half the time you just
studying languages what's the
point so ideally you should have one or
two languages at most and then if you
want to learn other foreign languages it
should be done on your own free time not
on it should not be part of a curriculum
So eventually the government needs to do
that and I am very clear about this that
the civilization language national
language has to be Sanskrit and now once
again lots of people will well be happy
with that well whether you like it or
not the civilization language has always
been Sanskrit and that needs to be
revived so whenever that happens it will
have to start at the lowest level from
from nursery and it should take 20 years
to go all the way up so each each year
you add one level to it so first year
you introduce that in in Nursery the
lowest level second you second year you
introduce in junior kg then Senior kg
then first standard second third
standard and so on over over a time of
one generation you can introduce it all
across the system that's how that's
that's a simple way of doing it
obviously everything can be made as made
to look as simple as you want to make it
look obviously it's complicated but it's
got to be done at some point in time if
we want to truly rise as a
civilizational entity or so it's for us
to decide do we want to remain a nation
state or do we want to embrace who we
really are a civilization state right so
there you have
it so now here's uh an interesting
question by prit MRE why were Indians so
historically non-martial people why
don't we have Indian chingis Khan
Napoleon and Khalid Walid have you heard
of samudra gupt samudra Gupta was a an
emperor of the Gupta dynasty about
roughly 1500 years before today roughly
give or take a couple of centuries if
you are interested in knowing exactly
when he lived and ruled Google it okay I
don't have dates you know stuck in my
mind so roughly 15600 years ago samudra
his entire career his entire career was
an extended military campaign okay he
unified the whole of
India so that is and and you had Kumar
Gupta who who conquered bik what is
called today called bulk he kicked the
Arabs out of the region he defeated them
what about
uh what okay then we have the the the
Kota Dynasty uh what's his name name why
why do names sometimes elude
me uh who was the greatest King of the
Kota Dynasty can somebody remind me in
the live chat come on live chat somebody
remind me who's
the king of the Kota
Dynasty Kota Dynasty kot mtia yes dongar
Singh Chan thank you so much I
appreciate that MTI m m mtia so this guy
he conquered Central Asia and your
textbooks will not write about him they
will not teach you about that your your
teachers will probably they don't even
know about him this guy conquered
Central Asia large parts of Central Asia
you would you do it through peace and
nonviolence or would you need military
conquest have you heard of the cholas
have you heard of the Chas the Chas
conquered southeast Asia all the way to
the
Philippines okay isn't that an example
of being a martial
race yes so and and who else do we have
scand once again going back to the Gupta
era scand Gupta spent his entire life
defending India from wave after wave of
hnik invasions the Sha hunas the the the
the white Huns they were invading they
were attempting to invade India at the
same time that they were succeeding in
invading Rome and destroying the Roman
Empire that's how widespread the the we
yeah we haven't cracked open the map I
mean what am I doing okay so let's crack
open the map uh where's the map here's
the map let's understand what the the
Sha hunas were doing the Huns okay here
we are so Rome the Roman Empire was in
Europe
obviously and we we are here in India
the scha hunas the white Huns were
attempting to invade India from the
north at the same time as they were the
same time that they were succeeding in
destroying the Roman Empire in Europe
and scand
Gupta he took a wow he said that I will
not sleep sleep on a bed and I will not
eat from a plate as long as I as I have
not uh you know ended this threat to my
nation so he he decided he will only
sleep on the ground and he will only eat
from a leaf as long as the threat exists
and he spent his entire life
fighting and repelling repulsing the
Huns and he
succeeded then what about the marata
Empire I mean they reconquered and and
you know uh they liberated India from
the
Turks in the 18th century was that not
um an example of being Marshal people so
it's not about One race you know the
British introduced this this disgusting
concept of Martial races that there are
they they they first of all put forth
the notion that still exists in among
Indian Minds that India is a nation of
multiple races of people you have the
jats you have the rajputs the maratas
and you have God knows whatever the p
and and whatever you know yeah so and
certain races among these people are
Marshal races so the the British
ascribed this term martial race to
certain people and others were
non-martial races apparently and all of
this is permeated through our education
system and this has put all these
Notions in our head that Indians are a
nation of losers and we have never you
know conquered other lands there is this
very popular notion on social media that
India hasn't invaded another country for
in the past 2 2,000 3,000 years what
utter nonsense what utter nonsense so I
mean I can give you so many more
examples but please understand that if
you study history then you will find
that none of these things are true so
obviously we did not have chingis Khan
obviously we do not have that Napoleon
you know what they call some idiots call
samudra Gupta the Napoleon of India
samudra Gupta lived way before Napoleon
it should be Napoleon who the samudra
Gupta of of of Europe uh and so on so
we've had
tremendous conquerors we've had people
who conquered Central
Asia multiple times we' have had rulers
who who conquered the whole of Southeast
Asia there was even a king in Manipur
what was his name kaga or something who
conquered Yan China there have been
Kings of Manipur who conquered Burma who
conquered Mandel and so on so there have
been so many examples but we are not
taught this the education teach system
doesn't teach us this that's why we keep
on believing that we are a nation of
losers we never did anything great and
all we did was what whatever all right
so please disabuse yourself of of these
Notions and the
antidote to this is to
read you know there's a thing about
podcast and all that you
know what I'm trying to say is that you
cannot really
learn deep Knowledge from a
podcast or from a show like this from a
show like this the ask show or from any
podcast that you watch you may get
inspiration you may get nuggets of of of
of knowledge or wisdom but you will
never get deep knowledge there is no
substitute for deep reading okay so if
you genuinely are interested in knowing
about your own history read and then you
will ask me where what do I read read
everything give yourself a time of five
or 10 years it's not something you can
do over or two weeks right you can't do
this over two weeks you got to invest
time if you genuinely serious about this
give yourself a time of 5 to 10 years
read everything you can find and much of
it will be garbage I I promise you that
much of it will be garbage especially
when it comes to Indian history you will
start with the Wikipedia which is full
of lies and you will look at other
sources on the internet many of them
could be completely wrong then you will
read actual books many of these books
when it comes to Indian history are full
of misinformation and distortions but if
you read enough then you will start to
see
patterns and you will start
understanding where the distortions are
but only if you read enough so it takes
time okay but you got to do it all right
good question and it's it's an important
question to to to take up all
right
um oh okay funny clips funny clipse says
which area country race Etc has the best
human genetics well let me give you a
bunch of
Statistics you take any two random human
beings okay from the surface of this
planet planet that we live
on wherever geographically once again
let's let's pick up the map let's crack
open the map where is the map here is
the
map okay let me just spin the map and
randomly Point here okay okay I've
pointed at which place it is in South
Africa okay one person from South Africa
random person and let's spin the map
again and I'll take it from here okay
didn't didn't go anywhere once again let
me spin it again and okay now we're
going to have somebody from Quebec so
take a person from a random person from
Quebec and take a random person from
South Africa and you do a DNA test you
decode their genome and what you will
find what you will find my friends is
that 99.9% of the genome is going to be
identical it's going to be
0.1% or maybe less than that that that
will be different
okay so essentially we are the we are
almost the same and obviously there's
going to be the there's going to be
variations based on location based on
climate based on how humans have had to
adapt in various parts of the world so
if you go to the northern latitudes in
in northern hemisphere what I'm talking
about is Siberia and Mongolia and these
places then you will find that there's a
lot of very harsh sunlight that's
reflected of the Snows over there
because it's always snowing there the
snow never really melts and because of
that you need to really squint your eyes
so over thousands of years humans
developed the
a mutation of having smaller eyes and
you know thin eyes I slanted eyes
whatever you want to call it okay and
that's why you have people from the
mongolic regions and all China Mongolia
Japan the higher latitudes you have even
in Northern America the true natives of
this region they all have small eyes you
know the the what do we call it I don't
remember what it's called that the
technical term for it uh epicanthal
folds or whatever the it's called so
that then when it comes to people who
live near the equator because of the
tremendously harsh sunlight that you get
24 I mean 365 days a year half the day
because of that people have developed
higher amounts of melanin than melanin
that's why people have darker skin near
the equator as you go nor northwards or
southwards you have lighter skin and
then depending on the kind of terrain
you have whether it is hilly terrain or
mountainous terrain or flat terrain and
how much nutrition you get you had
different kinds of you know um human
phenotypes that have occurred so each of
these adaptations is perfect for that
environment so there is not such thing
as Superior genetics or or inferior
genetics I mean if you look at the
adaptation in the adaptations in the
jungles of of Congo you have people who
are very short the so-called pigi people
right they have adapted perfectly well
for that environment you ask a six foot
tall person from Northern India or
Southern India or any other place to
live there for 20 years that person may
not be able to survive in that
environment so there's not such thing as
best genetics right genetics wrong
genetics okay it's not always true that
if you are 6 feet 3 Ines tall you are
superior to somebody who's 5' 7 that's
not the case what really matters is what
you do with your life okay and today I
mean I mean if you look at the Mongolian
people okay someone gave the example of
chingis Khan the great Shri chingis Khan
Defender Of Peace so someone gave the
example of chingis Khan if you look at
the average Mongolian person that the
average Mongol person is not a tall
person male let's say male I'm not sure
what the average height in Mongolia is
among males must be 56 57 I'm guessing
maybe I'm wrong okay the Mongolians
defeated the Russians repeatedly they
took over Russia the average height of
Russians I would imagine would be six
feet or something so how did a
supposedly inferior race of people
defeat a supposedly Superior race of
people Europeans that do so understand
it's not about how what you what your
what Your superficial features are like
uh so that's a deal so I don't believe
any area any country any race has better
genetics or any race has inferior
genetics it's all it all matters on your
conditions your circumstances of life if
you look at Africa today people get very
little there are lots of places in
Africa where people get very less
nutrition which is going to impair their
development which means that they will
not have the best physique and their
mental development may be uh impeded and
that's when PE people do this so-called
IQ test and they say that Africans have
low IQ whatever what nonsense it depends
on so many more factors than what they
are taking into account so I believe
there is no such thing as Superior or
inferior
genetics it all depends on what you do
with your life and whether you succeed
in Rising to the fullest extent of your
individual potential and the Nations
that do that they rule the world all
right
okay dongar Singh Johan asks where are
the descendants of these great Empires
like the moras guptas ETC so when it
comes to the Moria Empire it emerged out
of magad magad which is present day
Bihar okay present day Bihar and the
capital of the moras was partly Putra
today it's called
Patna okay so Patna today's Patna
historical ply Putra was the capital of
India at the time of the Moria samr
Moria Empire which was founded by Shri
Chandra Gupta MAA with the help of his
great mentor Shri vishnugupta
chanakya and later you had an even
greater Emperor which was chra Shri
chandragupta maa's grandson Shri Ashok
Moria one of India's greatest Emperors
and who genuinely unified the entire
subcontinent Ashoka spent his youth as
the as the governor of of gandhar which
is
Afghanistan and so on so so the U
capital of the Mora era India was
patliputra when it comes to the Gupta
era India Gupta Empire once again it
emerged out of patliputra out of out of
magad present day Bihar and then later
they had their capital I believe in
where was it matura was it or somewhere
I don't remember right now but you can
look it up I'm sure you you're able to
Google that so
the great Empires were made up
of I mean whether it's the Moria Empire
or the Gupta Empire both these Empires
encompassed the whole of the Indian
subcontinent and often times beyond that
for example the guptas like I said they
conquered bik which is Afghanistan and
Central Asia Tajikistan turkistan that
region they I think it was Kumar Gupta
who did that if I am not mistaken I
don't remember right now but you can
always look it up and so on so they this
Soldiers the the generals the
administrators of these Empires you
cannot run an ad an Empire through one
person the emperor understand that an
Empire isn't made up of one person the
emperor an Empire is an extensive
Arrangement it needs an effective
bureaucracy it needs a an an effective
system of administration that that is
spread all across the geography of the
of the of the Empire you need an
education system system you need
Educators high quality Educators you
need Merchants Artisans Crafts People
you need soldiers generals infantry
people you need
Sailors you
understand these Empires were made up of
our
ancestors all of
them yeah uh if you were we're asking
about the descendants of the Emperors
well I'm not sure whether they we have
lost the the record of the lineages
right the royal lineages
uh historically I think there were 36
Royal Clans in India right the uh
aristocratic clans of India I think
what's his name James Todd I think it
was the British guy who had made a list
of the 36 Aristo Royal clans of India
and these these lineages have been go
have been in existence since the late
Vic era so the lineages go go all the
way back to the Vic era Kings today the
monarchy system has been destroyed by
the by the modern post 1947 government
of India um so that's that's how it is
so we have lost many of the records of
these lineages you know I'm sure we had
entire records year by year and and
person after person of which king came
succeeded whom which king preceded whom
and so on king queen whatever but we've
lost that so today I would imagine that
many people in these parts of India
would be
descendants of some Emperor or the other
a little bit of ancestry would be
there some of them would be perhaps
fortunate enough fortunate enough to
know about it but many of them would not
even know about it I'm sure lots of
Indians are descended from Lord Ram it's
very much
likely okay because Lord Ram would have
lived several thousand years ago and if
you I mean think about it you live today
you have two
parents you have four
grandparents you have eight great
grandparents so that is over and and 16
great great grandparents and that is
something that happens over a period of
100 years only four generations or five
generations depending on whether it's 20
years or 25
years you go back a thousand years you
have tens of thousands of ancestors you
go back 3,000 years just imag imagine
how many an you have essentially
everybody who lived at that time would
have contributed something to your
genetics okay if you see it that way
you'll realize that all of us have some
ancestry that that goes back to the
Emperors and kings and queens ruled
ancient India going back to the times of
Shri Krishna and Shri Ram definitely so
if you think about that that that puts
things in a certain perspective we are
all the descendants of these great kings
and queens and Emperors and empresses
all of us we all have some genetic
contribution from them that is the
answer okay but Anisha says only sua Wes
would be descendants of Lord Ram not
Chandra Wes okay so let's say see Lord
Ram had two sons right love and Kush and
the cities of Lor and
kasur which are currently temporarily in
Pakistan are named after these two kings
because they themselves are Kings in
their own right and they would have had
descendants now their petral descent
would be suryan correct because every
time you have a son that son is going to
carry forward the lineage And that son
is sui but what if you have obviously
they would have some daughters as well
daughters Grand granddaughters and all
and those girls would go and marry among
other clans Chandra VES and whatever
other
VES yes which would mean that a Surya
wansi king would also have chandrai and
other wansi descendants
understand Anisha G okay so a lineage
doesn't isn't a single line of descent
it's an entire network it's an entire
net of
descendants so the single patrini
lineage of the successor Kings would be
be this sui lineage I believe the janua
rajputs are are considered to be
descendants of the of Lord Ram or
whatever that's what I've heard but you
would have so many other vanes that
would also have genetic contributions
from from Lord Ram please understand it
that in that manner so yeah that's a
deal
okay supria says can you explain the
mystery of the missing flight MH370 of
the Malaysian Airlines look if I knew
the the the the solution the the the
answer to the
mystery well
then see the fact is no one knows I'm
sure there are people who know I'm sure
there are some people who know what
happened but I don't so look it happened
a long time ago and the transponders on
the aircraft were Switched Off which
means that those aircraft were only
visible to military Radars that aircraft
was only visible to military Radars um
so when it comes to a military radar it
is the military Radars don't care
whether a plane's transponder is
switched on or off they just ping you
know they get the pings back from the
physical frame of the aircraft and
that's all the look for uh so from a
military Radar's perspective you cannot
tell what aircraft it is what its serial
number is and all that you can only kind
of Judge the size of the aircraft the
altitude of the aircraft and the speed
and direction of the
aircraft so this aircraft was visible on
Military
Radars but it was invisible to
commercial uh Radars for commercial
aircraft and it looks like it could have
taken two
arcs two paths after the transort Wonder
was switched off one could have gone
northwards into Central Asia another
went as we know would have gone into the
Indian
Ocean and we don't quite know what
happened and it is believed that it it
essentially went all the way deep into
the southern Indian Ocean and maybe it
crashed over there once it ran out of
fuel that's the belief and uh there have
been accusations made against Mr zahari
um I forget the Pilot's name the
captain's name but zahari Ahmed or
Muhammad or something Malaysian Captain
he has been accused of being the guy who
did this you know pilot suicide which is
something that's not extremely uncommon
unfortunately so it's happened in the
past that some Pilots wanted to commit
suicide and they took the entire plane
and the passengers with them it happened
in the uh not very long ago German Wings
crashed and there have been there was an
incident recently in China as well in
which a plane just doed Dove down
straight
down that was most likely a pilot
suicide so maybe this zahari Ahmed thing
was also a pilot suicide that's the
theory that's been put out I'm not sure
what the answer
is hopefully someday we'll get to the
bottom of this mystery as to what
happened where is the whatever is left
of the aircraft where is it located is
it in the Indian Ocean somewhere else
not sure but I I don't have the answer
sorry um Sania Singh says I am a rajput
I am really interested in world history
but somehow I am unaware of the history
of my own ancestors well that's the
story of all Indians you know that the
history we are taught is the history of
Alexander the Great Alexander the Greek
maybe Julius Caesar okay great man but
complete genocidal Maniac Okay by the
way Julius Caesar we tgh about I don't
know what other world history and then
we T about the history of our oppressors
and colonizers which is the so-called
mugul Empire which was in power for two
and a half centuries three centuries
maximum but we are made to believe that
it's all of Indian history and then we T
taught about the British colonizers of
India and how they reformed India and
made India better apparently allegedly
which is all a lie but we are not taught
of our own history and that's why Indian
kids find history so boring because
there is nothing that they can relate to
I mean you we are being taught about
Shah Jahan and jangar all these tur
barbarians you not taught of your own
history I mean who are the Indian
people what is the origin of the Indian
people what Journey have our ancestors
taken what hardships have our ancestors
faced what victories did our ancestors
win what wonderful things did our
ancestors contribute to the world and if
I'm let's say living in in let's say in
in Telangana or let's say I'm living in
Assam or let's say I'm living in uh
let's say Rajasthan I would like to know
the local history what happened here in
the past 2,000 years 3,000 years years
we not taught any of that so we simply
can't relate to that that's why kids
have no interest in history I myself
went through this as a kid all this the
you know the lists of mugal Emperors and
all that but I thankfully my curiosity
wasn't destroyed I would read history
books that were outside of the syllabus
and that's how I I found that's why
that's why history was always
interesting to me so I totally
understand Sania what what your
situation is we are not taught our
history these days there is a little bit
that start about marata history little
bit maybe a page or two but typically
the entire book is about is going to
talk about the history of the British
Invaders and the turkic Invaders once
again when it comes to Raju history
you're not even taught what is the
origin of the rajs that there are 36
Royal Clans I mean in
India and and so on you not taught
anything so obviously you will not find
history interesting and what's the
solution I don't know I mean ideally the
Indian government should publish the
right kind of textbooks that teach
actual Indian history factual Indian
history based on actual evidence not
opinions of various so-called imminent
historians in the absence of that since
that is not the case since the those
textbooks aren't there I guess you will
have to maybe look up I don't know RC
majumdar or those ancient historians who
wrote a century ago but those books are
still reasonably okay uh they have good
information and you can look up genetic
data and all that but that is very hard
to interpret so yeah I know that's a
situation we all all Indian kids go
through today you know teenagers
children young adults old adults
everybody you just don't know what to
what to make of your own history
hopefully over time the situation
improves but I would say that at least
read world history that's also
interesting yeah all
right okay what do we have I don't even
know what this is so just need sing says
what's the story of anun anun anun what
are you I've heard this term lots of
times anunaki I think they call it I
don't know what that is it seems to be
some mythological thing that came out of
the Middle
East um the Hebrew culture or or or
Mesopotamian culture or something some
mythological supernatural beings of some
kind I don't know what that is okay I
mean I've not studied that part of
History I'm not sure if it's even
history I think it's
mythology you know beings with
Supernatural powers and all that that's
obviously mythology that's not not
history so that's what I know about it
and that's all I can say about it
yeah tan seal says if Maldives decides
to give China a proper military base
would India think to invade Maldives
uh so the Maldives Mal's government has
been uh you know uh Mr Pazuzu is in
power right Mr Pazuzu his name or
muu Pazuzu whatever his name is muuu
perhaps so Mr muuu is the current uh
leader of the malds and he is very
strongly anti-india and pro China
obviously he's getting money from China
I promise you that the Chinese are
bribing him filling his pockets and his
coffers and he has recently acquired
some drones from
Turkey what by buy car drones or
something and he has ordered the Indian
military to to leave the country and uh
yeah he is very strongly pro-china so
the question is what happens if the
Maldives decides to give China a proper
military base I think it would be
unacceptable to India obviously the
Maldives are currently a Sovereign
Nation let's see how long because
eventually they'll be swallowed up by
the Sea if the sea level rise which
could happen and then they will
obviously want to gain shelter in India
we'll see about that when when it comes
to
that um if the Chinese uh acquire a base
in the Maldives I think it will cross
several Indian red lines and maybe India
will take some action but I would not
want to talk about what action India
would take I don't want to talk about
India invading Nations I don't think
India would invade a nation unless it
poses a direct threat to India's
national
interests uh but there are lots of ways
in which you could counter any such
thing by China I mean you could
essentially you know even the the
Chinese May acquire let's say
hypothetically a base in the Maldives
you could blockade the base navally
Naval blockade the Chinese could protest
or let them protest you know and so on
so there are lots of there's a whole
graded
escalation ladder that exists that we
can come up with if if such a thing were
to happen but obviously it would be
unaccept unacceptable to India for the
for the Chinese to have a military base
the Maldives that is for sure the
Chinese already have a military base in
the coko islands uh for example so so
the Maldives are south of the lakwe
archipelago they essentially are a
continuation of the lakad
archipelago the British Indian Ocean
territory is also a continuation of the
same archipelago the shago archipelago
is a continuation of that of the
Maldives in the Maldives are
continuation of the lakad islands so you
have Maldives here and then the Chinese
already have a basee a military
base uh in the northern Coco Island
which one is it
this uh let's go to the uh no it's not
this one it's this one here so this
these Islands belong to India the great
magnificent Shri jawaharlal Neu G gifted
it to Burma these two islands and today
you have a Chinese military base over
here which you can clearly see see in
the satellite
images okay it is nominally run by Burma
but it's actually operated with the
chines that's this
Observatory and uh this this air strip
over here and there are listening
stations and
whatnot and
uh yeah there's a significant amount of
infrastructure that the Chinese have
built on this island do we have anything
here I'm not sure but there would be
some presence over here as you can see
there's a road here on the southern on
the little KOCO Island so there's
something over here as well so this is
all thanks to the great magnificent Shri
javahar Lal Neu G so the Chinese already
have a presence here uh recently when
India conducted the ag5 test with mirv
technology the Chinese had a couple of
spice ships that were tasked with
collecting electronic intelligence about
the flight
parameters of the missile and the and
the contents of the missile so yeah the
Chinese would very much love to have
some kind of asset over here but that
would not be acceptable to India and
let's see what India does about this but
I'm not sure that we would want to
invade the Maldives unless it becomes
entirely U
unavoidable so yeah that's a deal okay
let's take some all some more
questions some more questions
okay om Su says how can we develop
leadership qualities and become a
civilizational political leader a leader
needs to have a tremendous range of
abilities so what does it mean to be a
leader do you have to be a do you have
to be six feet tall do you have to have
a loud voice to be a leader do you have
to be physically intimidating and scary
to be a leader not really what is
leadership is the question well
leadership simplest answer about
leadership is that leadership is
service leadership is
service but service in a way that you
multiply with with the force multiply
effect by bringing other people on board
your mission and having them obey you
for the larger interest of the of
the of the people of the country yeah
and obviously you need to know know how
to handle people you need to know how to
face adversity you need to know how to
handle criticism you need to know how to
handle opponents adversaries there are
so many things that you to learn you to
learn how to organize people you to have
organizational skills you need to have
all kinds of skills to be a political
leader and to be a civilization
political leader you have to be grounded
in your civilization as well so the
thing about leadership is that
leadership is service you cannot you
will not be a genuine leader if you have
a hidden agenda and if you have a
conflict of interests that I'm serving
the people but I'm also using it to to
further my agenda and to and to somehow
benefit me personally that should not be
the
case um so there's so much that that is
part that goes into being a
leader uh so understand so if you're
just starting off and you want to be a
leader if I'm not sure you initially you
will not even know if you have those if
you are capable of being one
the thing is uh you need to be able to
talk you need to be able to speak in
public most people you put them in front
of 20 people they'll be frightened to
speak you put them put a person on a
stage in front of 50 people that person
is going to be frightened most people
will be trembling and listen that's not
a bad thing I think it's a natural human
reaction so what you have to do is to
you have to embrace the fear you have to
embrace discomfort and learn how to
thrive in such situations and all that
that only comes to practice repeated
practice uh so one thing one
indispensable ability that every leader
needs to every great leader has is the
ability to communicate verbally to
connect with large numbers of
people one to one Charisma all that
there's so much that goes into
leadership but you I would say that you
have to start by having the mindset of
service that you want to
serve leading means to serve I mean you
know a person who cleans a street every
day on his own vition or her own vition
is serving the people and is in a very
small way leading Society in in that
small that small locality the street you
know but if you want to make the effect
larger you have to take other people on
board which means you to inspire people
to follow you so there's so much that
goes into leadership maybe I should
write a book about this or an article
about this yeah uh so yeah so start with
the mindset of of service you want to
serve Society you want to serve the
people oh
right om beica says what was the main
reason behind the disintegration of
Yugoslavia okay let's go to the map
where is the map so
Yugoslavia is used to be east of Italy
today you have these nations here right
the the Balkan Nations Croatia Serbia
Bosnia and that's
Montenegro North Macedonia Slovenia all
that all that was a single nation called
Yugoslavia uh essentially a bunch of
Slavic peoples within a single nation
and Yugoslavia was well most people
would say most historians would say was
a satellite state of the
USSR and it essentially existed and
operated under the protection umbrella
of the USSR it was a war so packed
Nation the other nations were you know
essentially Poland and and and so on
Hungary and all that uh the Eastern
European nations Roman Romania as well
so uh and then you also had another
Nation called Czechoslovakia which has
also broken up so after the
disintegration of the USSR what happened
is that this umbrella of protection
disappeared and then obviously the
Americans the West because the Americans
had won the Cold War so they had to
bring it home to the people that we are
now ruling we are now in charge and
we're going to do what we think is right
we're going to change things for you
we're going to change things and your
life will change your countries will
change Everything Will Change since we
are the winners we're going to decide
and because of various factors such as
these the nation of Yugoslavia broke
up so if you I mean you could do a two
hour three hour lecture about the
sequence of events and all that but if
you ask me the main reason the main
reason behind the disintegration of
Yugoslavia was that their their main
protector and benefactor the USSR itself
disintegrated in 1991 and then the
Americans took control of the whole of
Europe because Russia was very weak at
the time became it became very weak its
economy collapsed you had a ineffect
ineffectual leader in Boris Yen running
the show who was essentially a western
agent so the Americans had the run of
the whole of Europe at the time and they
decided to change things around and then
you had the entire Balkan conflict the
Kosovo Serbia all that stuff that
happened in the the late 90s early 2000s
all that you know Saro mosar if anyone
remembers uh all that so the main reason
is firstly the collapse of the USSR and
secondly the Americans deciding to
change things in this region
okay
um okay what else do we
have uh sidan Singh says should be worry
about the apus asteroid I'm not sure
what the path of this asteroid is what
kind of orbit it has I have not looked
into it but I am sure that there are a
bunch of asteroids that are classified
as near Earth asteroids which means that
their orbit kind of coincides with the
orbit of the Earth but not always at the
same time so the orbits May intersect
but so that means that over lots of
orbits you may have a close interaction
between the Earth and so and so asteroid
is apice one of them I'm not sure but if
it is in that case we should keep a very
close eye on that and we should
calculate its future orbits as far into
the future as possible the next let's
say 10,000 orbits or whatever I'm sure
you can do it it's not it's not a big
deal all you need is to use Newtonian
mechanics and you can use computers to
do that you don't have to calculate the
paths by
hand uh so I'm sure I'm aware that there
is a a database of near Earth
objects uh object of particular concern
that is constantly
monitored and there are a few near
misses in the future in the in the next
20 30 years I'm not sure if apace is one
of those the real danger is not from
these known objects the near real danger
is from unknown objects that we may have
missed because the night sky is dark
these objects are Bunch pieces of rock
essentially you know half a kilometer 1
kilometer 5 kilometer and if you the
distances are enormous millions of
kilometers it's almost impossible to see
them so you have these telescopes that
keep on tracking these objects and once
in a while you come up with you see a
new object and then you start tracking
that so that's what you do the danger is
not from the objects that are known and
that are being tracked the danger is
from the objects that we have not
discovered yet because those could be
the ones that could possibly
POS a
threat and we know that in the in the
past we've had these impact events
significant impact
events uh we had one about a decade ago
chelia bins in in Russia in Siberia
which was not really a very uh very
significant event in in in the in the
sense that it didn't did not kill anyone
it broke a lot of Windows and all that
in 1908 you had the the the
the tunguska event which again happened
in in Siberia and I don't think there
were any casualties but it was much more
powerful than the cheliabinsk
event uh but in the past if you go back
to a time frame of millions of years
we've had
tremendously life-changing events like
the chuk shub impact that happened about
66 million years ago which led to the
extinction of the nonavian
dinosaurs and these events happen every
maybe 60 70 maybe 100 million years this
massive uh Extinction event level
impacts So that obviously will happen in
the future it could happen next week it
could happen in the next 30 million
years we don't know so we have to be
ever
Vigilant and uh I'm sure there are
government agencies apart from the
Americans that are also keeping track of
these objects so yeah we have to be
cautious we have to be always vigilant
all
right
uh okay what else do we
have okay this is by assassins Fox why
Wars weren't affecting ancient and
medieval kingdoms but are affecting
today's economy well okay depends on on
the context when it comes to Wars in
Europe that did affect the economy
because in in it all depends on how how
you fight War when when it came to India
pre-invasion
India I'm talking about the pre-t turkic
invasions and pre- British Invasion pre
so I'm talking about India before the
past 10,000 years okay so before in in
the pre-invasion India uh wars were
would typically happen over territorial
disputes or some other dispute but the
the wars would invade would involve the
armies of the two opposing forces the
two opposing Powers let's say one
Kingdom in India fought another kingdom
in India or
whatever they would never devastate
cities they would never touch
civilians so that was the way Indians
fought
War so when you don't destroy cities
when you don't destroy crops when you
don't destroy trade routes when you
don't kill civilians it doesn't affect
the
economy okay to a large extent obviously
an army which is on a campaign will need
lots of food and sustainance
to uh to conduct its military campaign
so that would have some effect on the
economy but as long as there's no
destruction of Civilian areas there will
be minimal impact on the economy so
that's how Indians used to fight Wars
obviously they they were Wars between
kingdoms and all that but they would
never touch civilians that was the way
Indians fought War it all changed after
the Arabic and turky invasions in which
civilians were Fair targets and that is
what started the decline of the Indian
economy so that's why
the wars that happened within India in
Ancient India did not really affect the
Indian economy when it came comes to
Europe okay you had the 100 Years War
and you had all if you look at the the
history of Europe it's a history of Wars
like small Wars big Wars Petty Wars
Tribal wars just a constant history of
Wars these wars that the Europeans
fought they they would
plunder uh civilian areas they would
burn cities and towns and Villages and
they would kill civilians and enslave
civilians and they would plunder the
area they would burn crops they would
take away as much wealth as possible I
mean you see that all the time and that
is something that will obviously affect
the economy okay so it depends on the
context on the region on the country on
the culture all that today when it comes
to War I mean let's take the Iraq War
for example the American invasion of
Iraq 2003 what kind of war was that it
was a war of flattening an entire nation
the Americans went in full with what
they call shock and O and they flattened
Bagdad they flattened the they flattened
I don't know Basra they flattened every
city they came across simply smashed The
Living Daylights out of out of the city
and then they would not publish what
happened the aftermath they would only
publish high level images not not what
happened to the civilians obviously the
Civ civilians seized to exist as living
entities right millions of them uh at
least a million Iraqis died so when you
destroy an entire city an entire nation
it's going to destroy the
economy it all depends on what kind of
War you fight what is your method of
fighting Warfare if you use shock and O
if you flatten entire nations it's going
to destroy the economy so it all depends
on that right so if you so so that's the
answer so it all depends on how you
fight how you choose to fight war and
obviously it it takes two to tango you
want to fight a war that doesn't affect
civilians but your enemy wants to
destroy your entire nation and enslave
all your people that's very two very
different
approaches so it takes two to tangle so
that is how Wars affect or do not affect
economies okay
um is good question this yes gaming
lover says why are Indian cities so
dirty and unhygienic
even the holiest and sacred rivers are
so polluted how can it be improved good
question right is this because we
Indians have an inferior culture and we
have inferior standards or is there some
other reason behind
this so the reason why the Indian cities
I I'm not specifying taking any specific
cities name let's see a random
hypothetical Indian city why is it so
dirty and unhygienic because the godamn
municipal Corporation is corrupt
okay they're not doing what they're
supposed to
do their job is to have a proper system
of of waste collection a proper system
of Maintenance they have such huge
budgets there's no shortage of money but
what happens where does the money go
what is it allocated for what is it
utilized for that's the
question and you will say that why don't
the people take care of this in India
everybody struggles to earn a living
India is a lowincome nation
okay you have to travel two hours a day
in a large city or four hours a day just
to commute between your your house and
your place of work and you're working
four five six seven days a week you have
no time or energy to go out and clean
the the
roads okay people are still in India
still still still struggling just to
just for subsistence India is not a high
income Nation when everyone is sub
struggling just to maintain a very low
standard of living and hopefully save
some money and give the children a
better future do you think they will
have the time to go and clean up the
city and the streets and all that ah the
people don't have any standards no the
system is such that they have trapped
Indians in this in this low wage slavery
system okay things are obviously
changing but I'm talking about the past
70 80 years since Independence how
things
were there was there was nothing you
could do about it the entire system was
corrupt
and if you refus to pay bribes or
whatever then you would go through hell
so people obviously will take the the
easy way out pay a bribe and just ignore
what's happening out there and do
whatever you can for your family so that
that's when people become close-minded
and they start looking inwards and they
just you know every every person every
family for themselves that's how it
becomes it's because of the corrupt
system I'm not talking about any
specific City let me repeat this just
hypothetical any random city in the
country it's because there's a lot of
money and all the money is used for God
knows what it is not used for what it it
should be used for okay and then there
are places where they'll say that you
need to segregate uh different kinds of
waste okay dry waste and solid waste and
whatnot and and wet waste okay so
they'll they'll make you segregate your
waste and and and and put it in
different bins and all that but at the
end of the day they're going to dump it
all in the same landfill or the same
river and and that's just the way it is
okay the system has been built in such a
way that it's just horrible that's a
long way to go for India to
improve and this entire
um um this entire system of of dumping
you know sewage into
rivers I think it was the British that
started that India you know India is a
river valley civilization every single
river is Holy and sacred in India every
river and the British started started
the
practice of dumping Rose sewage into
rivers including the ganga the yamuna
the cavari all the all the great sacred
holy rivers of
India and after
1947 the the deracinated secular
government of India expanded this
practice to every single city in India
so you'll find that every single city in
India I'm I'm sure there must be some
hopefully that they don't do it but most
C in India simply dump
sewage into either the rivers or into
the
ocean so this is because of the low
standards of the people who are running
the country I'm not talking about the
the guy at the top he's trying to change
things I'm talking about the
lowlevel ground
level uh administration of India the
people who actually run things on the
ground I'm sure there are some of them
also who are good okay I'm not saying
everybody is bad I'm not saying
everybody is corrupt but this is
something that needs to be changed there
needs to be a war in India against
corruption and low standards
unfortunately it's a top- down process
that so it's it's happening it'll take
maybe another 5 10 20 years for things
to come all the way down to the ground
level but I
am I'm optimistic because I know what
what our standards used to be in the
past okay and that's something that's
encoded in our DNA
if you know you will see that Indians
when they go
abroad they are the most low abiding
people they are the least likely to
litter and make things dirty but in
India we have no choice so I would say
stop blaming the victims there are lots
of people who will disagree and I'm sure
I will be able to see comments that I'm
stupid and it is our own fault that this
is happening no we are trapped in a
system that we can't escape we are
simply trapped in the system and that's
why Indians have just given up over the
past few Generations just given
up we'll just live our lives and do what
we can and we'll escape and go abroad if
we can that's the deal that's what it
was so we need to change the standards
we need
to you know eradicate corruption and
malpractices is going to take time but
it will
happen right
um
okay prar says her opinion on Election
24 well I don't know I'm optimistic that
Mr Modi will win because I want Mr Modi
to win okay if Mr Modi Modi doesn't win
then it's it's it's curtains for India
curtains
bu so yes my opinion is that he will win
and I I I am very optimistic that he
will win and I would like him to win
call me whatever you want I am biased of
course I
am all
right um
sarvagna Sharma says is the current
system of democracy good for bhat if not
what other system would be good for us
and what and do you think it would it is
good to continue in English as our
official language English should
go I said this about half an hour ago 45
minutes ago in this live stream it's
said that English needs to go eventually
right now it's the dominant language in
the world but one day we make our
language the dominant language in the
world why
not a small island in the Atlantic Ocean
a little bunch of people they have you
know through imperialism impos their
language as the dominant language in the
world and they made Indians believe that
it's the only way you can progress in
the world we need to uh do something
about
that
um so we need to do something about that
uh so English is it is not good for
English to continue as an official
language in India it's it's the language
of Oppression it's the language of
colonialism it's a foreign language and
it has to go
right now we will use it right now we
will use the language of the oppressor
to put forth our narrative to put forth
our ideas and our views but eventually
we have to bring in our language
hopefully it happens within our
lifetimes is the current system of
democracy good for Barat look any I
don't care what system it is as long as
the nation progresses so if the current
system of democracy can do that great
see in the 21st century the Nations that
will rule the world lead the world are
the Nations that will make the most
advances the most rapid advances in
technology and also the Nations that
will make the quickest decisions and
Implement those decision decisions as
fast as possible so you can have a
leader who has the best ideas but if the
system is so corrupt and so rotten that
it cannot implement the decisions of of
of the leader or the government then
that system is bad and currently as we
know very well the Indian system needs a
significant overhaul I'm not saying
democracy is is bad or good I'm saying
the system that we have this entirely
cumbersome and very ancient outdated
obsolete bureaucratic system that we
have the rotten education system all
that needs to change okay democracy
there's nothing wrong with democracy
democracy was born in India but we had
our own form of democracy which did not
involve going that the leader of the
country has to go to the to has to stand
for elections every five years or
whatever was a different system India
had
a India had a Hy
system so you would have an emperor at
the topup morya keska kushan or scand
Gupta Kumar
Gupta samudra Gupta or or
[Music]
orapa or the cholas or whoever you would
have an emperor at the top and then you
would have democracy at the Grassroots
which mean that means the people would
elect their own officials at the
Grassroots who would handle things
locally right now it's a very different
system that was the system which we had
in India and if you look at the various
times in in in inan history in world
history when India has been supreme
power very powerful Nation great economy
and all that it's always been when India
was ruled by a dictator an
emperor so yeah there we go that's what
I can say about
this JP P says why is please divorce
among men and women increasing to
shocking levels in marriages thanks look
it's because in the west this is a
western thing in the
west it is believed that the
individual that the individual is the uh
unit of
society so it's all about individualism
this is a very Anglo-Saxon thing you
will see this attitude among the
Anglo-Saxons and the
Germans Germany obviously is a defeated
Nation it's a colonized Nation it's an
occupied so they don't matter anymore
the Germans but it's the Anglo Saxons
who rule the world the five eyes and who
rules the five eyes the US it's a very
anglosaxon thing this
individualism so according to them the
individual is the unit of society in
other parts of the world in other
civilizations in civilized places the
family is the unit of society not the
individual so when you place self above
everything
else and then then when you have these
ideas like the woke ideology the woke
mind virus that's prevalent in the west
today and all that and when you when
then when you take away culture and
religion out of the out of the mix of
society then you are left with no values
no moral Foundation by which no moral
framework by which to live life so then
people will go and cheat people will go
and you know have extramarital Affairs
or you would never get married you have
children out of marriage and all that
that that leads to a complete breakdown
of society and then the lowest values
become the most common values and that
what you're seeing in the west I mean
the kind of images you see in social
media videos and all that come out of
the West which now constitutes us
culture uh it makes me want to cringe so
it's because of this that there is such
a high rate of divorce among men and
women it used to be what in in
Christianity until death do us part
that's what they used to say the Wows
marriage in Christianity today it's
until divorce does US does a part which
is typically 6 months to two years and
then you get a new partner then you get
a new partner or you don't get married
and have 78 different partners over a
period of three months or whatever it's
it's it's crazy it reduces you down to
the level of almost animals I would say
you need to have standards in everything
and I believe that monogamy is a is is a
high standard to have yeah
uh yeah so because of the this breakdown
of values breakdown of culture the the
complete removal of any religion from
society obviously it's Christianity
that's been removed from Western Society
Christianity itself was an was a
forcible imposition on Western Society
but that's beside the point you need
some kind of moral found framework
whatever it is good bad inferior
Superior at least some kind of find
framework is there if you have that then
you know how to then you don't have to
think about how to live life you just
know that this is acceptable this is not
acceptable and today it's all about my
my free will my choice I decide what I
do with life I will everybody does drugs
everybody does promiscuous sex it's
crazy and that's why you have this High
rate of divorce among men and women and
you know the the bad effect of that is
that every child comes from a broken
family and children who come from a
broken family are way more like to do
drugs to to be abusive in relationships
to commit suicide to go to prison to
commit crime all that it's statistically
you know there have been so many studies
that that bear this out so what you
seeing is a is a Devolution Devolution
of society of societal standards in the
west now they're trying to export it to
the rest of the
world uh so yeah that's the situation
and that's why you have all these all
these these uh problems that have crept
into that are creeping into Western
society and they're trying to export it
worldwide I hope they
fail
okay theusa SAU says please tell us
about the fmr in the northeastern region
with uh with focus on nagaland what's
fmr I wonder
fmr not sure what fmr is let me just try
and Google what fmr is fmr full
form free movement regime free movement
regime free movement regime all right I
get it I get it so what's this free
movement regime in the northeastern
region of India the Far East of India
look okay let's go to the
map we have the map here okay let's go
back to India to Barat now you know why
is this region this particular region of
India called the Northeast I'll tell you
why it's called the Northeast the
British Invaders and occupiers of India
initially were based out of what is
today called Bengal okay and from their
location in Bengal this region was to
their Northeast from where they were
situated so they used to call this
region the Northeast later on the
British ruled all over all of India but
India's stupid idiotic historians kept
on repeating the old British terminology
and they kept on calling this region the
Northeast it's actually the Far East of
India from what perspective is it in the
north and east of India it's the Far
East of India it's the easternmost
extremity of India so it's not the
Northeast it's these idiot historians
the so-called imminent historians of
India who have kept on perpetuating this
outdated narrative from a British
perspective okay now the question is the
free movement regime the free movement
regime was this uh agree was this
understanding we had with the government
of Burma that we would not fence the
Border see Burma is a friendly Nation
okay Burma is culturally historically
very allied with India U so and it's
friendly Nation I mean we have had never
well never any real disputes with Burma
of any kind or any significant kind
since 1947 since the since the 20th
century
essentially so we've had we've had this
open border policy
say and uh the movement of people was
allowed across the border I mean you
could people from Burma could just walk
into India and stay for a certain number
of days and people from the Indian side
of the Border could walk into Burma and
stay for a specific number of days this
was called this is still called the free
movement regime in this region and this
applies to all the border states which
is arunachal Pradesh nagaland Manipur
and mizoram okay Visa Burma the
international border with Burma
Myanmar so that's the free movement
regime and now we're going to end that
because of the situation because you
know Millions not Millions but hundreds
of thousands of burmes U of of of of
individuals from Burma have moved into
essentially into Manipur okay and they
have
occupied a significant portion of
Manipur maybe more than 50% of Manipur
if you look at satellite images of over
the past 5 seven years you will see
thousands of new Villages that have
crept up that have come up and it is
alleged that many of them are coming
through mizoram so they enter through
mizoram allegedly and they are not
allowed to settle down in mizoram but
they are allowed to go northwards into
Manipur allegedly where they settle down
permanently and that has completely
transformed the demographics of this
region artificially which is
unacceptable and all the foreigners need
to go and this stupid Indian government
of the 20th century various governments
in the 1960s '70s Etc they have this
policy of settling these so-called
cookie refugees into in into into
Manipur for what reason I have no idea
obviously they just wanted to change the
religious and ethnic demographics of the
region so because of the situation today
which has been inherited by the current
government but it has not been created
by the current government because of
that now India has decided to end the
free movement regime and some some
states apparently I hear allegedly are
protesting against that I hear that
allegedly mizoram is allegedly
protesting against the ending of the
free movement regime they want to keep
the Border open for God knows what
reason but it is not their call they
don't get to decide a state doesn't get
to decide what happens at the
international border of India and that's
just the way it's going to be mizoram is
going it's another issue that needs to
be resolved it will be resolved properly
okay it will take time but it will be
resolved I will not go into missam right
now a very interesting case study
actually so and in nagaland also so
obviously the people who are called the
nagas the various tribes so many of them
live on the other side of the border and
historically they have had you know they
have been the same people so obviously I
I would expect that there would be some
some possible perhaps resistance from
nagaland also but look when it comes to
National Security we got to put the N
Nation first so the free movement regime
will end now it's going to take many
years to fence the Border properly and
to have the kind of patrolling that we
have on the Western border with the
temporary Nation called Pakistan
but it will be done so when it comes to
nagaland the FOC so the question is
focus on nagaland so look nagaland is
this region north of Manipur which is
made up of a large number of different
tribes who all speak different languages
historically U the many of them
lived possibly in a significant amount
of isolation for centuries that sort of
thing and uh this border I mean if you
go east of the international border you
will have the same many of the same
ethnic groups who live in northern Burma
who would be called nagas right uh
according to that
terminology uh so obviously the same
situation occurs in nagaland that people
would travel across the border which is
a good thing and a bad thing because you
know not very far from nagaland if you
cross Northern Burma you come to China
which is hardly uh let's see let's try
and calculate the distance
here if calculate the distance is about
300 kilm which is not a very significant
amount of territory so if you have free
movement then it is known that uh you
know various Insurgent groups separatist
groups which have been fighting the
government of India for decades in this
region have been supplied arms from
China and obviously this comes across
the border right so at some point in
time the government of India has to take
the call as to what is in the best
interest of the nation once the go of
Burma can properly take control of the
whole of the country then we could
possibly rethink this but right now we
definitely need an end to the free
movement regime so that we can you know
Safeguard the territorial interest of
India and and stop this ridiculous
influx of Kookie refugees into India and
then they acquire documentation and they
become Indian so there's going to be NRC
all that which will be done and the
foreigners will be evicted because we
need need Justice for the true for the
true IND Indians the true natives of of
India uh India is not some kind of
dhamala like they say that anybody can
come and just settle down squat in
Indian Territory and start demanding
rights so yeah this problem will be
solved but it's going to take time
minimum I would say 20 years it's a this
problem was created over more than a
Century's time okay by the British and
by then by the postc colonial government
of India post 47 governments of India
including the government of the great
Shri Jawal Neu this problem was created
then and this the current government has
inherited this problem and they are
trying to solve it if it's going to take
time the people of the region need to
understand that you need patience you
need to be patient you're going to have
to swallow a lot of pain for the next 10
20 years but yeah uh I'm pretty sure
this this problem will be solved by
evicting the foreigners from Indian
Territory Chand mandal says I a
supporter of of Arians from this land
all right but there's this word called
adasi that means someone who is from
this land since since the start doesn't
that explain that Arians were foreign
when okay good question the question is
this Chand G this term
adivasi when was this term coined when
was this term created do you find this
term in ancient Indian literature from
let's say 500 AD
you don't do you find this term in
Indian literature from from 1500 ad you
don't you don't do you find this term
this term adivasi in vic literature in
late Vic literature in post VC
literature in Pali literature in Canada
literature in prit literature you find
it
nowhere this is a neologism a term that
was created recently like in the past
100 or so years
okay and this ter was created to divide
Indians into Natives and
foreigners so the question that that you
that you're asking is pretty logical
good question so the to answer the
question all you have to do is take this
term adivasi and Trace its origin when
does it first appear in literature and
you will find that it appears in
colonial and postc Colonial literature
only
so it was a term that was recently
created with the objective of of
creating artificial divisions within
Indians and they have then they will say
that certain people are adasi and others
are not adasis and this's this new new
term that has come up these days mul
Nasi who gets to decide who is mul Nasi
and who is adivasi who gets to decide
these these so-called
professors who actually do know actual
research that's the thing and if you do
genetic analysis of people of India
you will find that the genetics of the
are essentially uniform across India
whether it is the so-called adasis or
the so-called mul nases or the so-called
dravidians or the so-called Arians they
all have the same
genetics so then what yeah so what they
do is that they want to Influence People
by creating
terms terms that that and because it
comes from Academia it looks very
genuine so you start believing yeah
adasi means those people must be the
original people and we our ancestors
must be our ancestors must be what
Invaders occupiers and since our
ancestors were Invaders and occupiers
who brought along Sanskrit and Hinduism
that means even Hinduism and srit is
foreign to India so then it's okay for
other foreign religions to also come
into India and and evict Hinduism and
Destroy Hinduism that is the objective
all right so uh creating a new term
doesn't make the natives of India
non-native all right think logically and
always try to trace back the origin of
any
term okay showcase says what do you
think about China claiming annif
distance to be more is it to weaken the
West's trust over India who cares
whether the West trusts India or not we
don't need anyone's
trust so the Chinese um I'm not sure
what they've
claimed look I I'll tell you about the
ug five
the government of India whether it is
drdo or whoever else have
never put out a
number and said that this is the range
that the ag5 missile has we have never
officially put out a range an official
figure of the range of the missile so it
is speculated that this missile has a
range between 5 and 10,000 kilometers
okay and recently we did a test and it
had the the notam the notice to Airmen
was that we had created this exclusion
Zone on so and so date where nobody must
go because if you go there you may be
hit by something and that range was not
a very long range but before that a few
months ago we had a range that went all
the way almost to Australia that was
possibly a different missile perhaps
okay nobody has gone and seen which
missile was tested but yeah so we have
we have maintained ambiguity about the
range of the missile and if somebody
says it's a 5,000 kilometer range
missile or somebody says 8,000 kilom
range missile they are
speculating only our scientists and our
government knows what the actual range
is and we have been developing missiles
for decades we we have some of the best
best missiles in the world there is
nothing that
prevents our scientists our Engineers
from developing a missile of any
arbitrary
range 5,000 km sure why not 10,000 we
can do it 15,000 yeah we can do it okay
so uh that's why the
Chinese they have been I don't know what
they've been claiming apparently they're
saying it's a 10,000 kilometer range
missile well good it better be so uh so
if you put the map on the
screen uh if you were to launch a
missile from let's say odisha okay and
let's just measure the distance from
odisa to let's say saporo in Japan it's
about 5,000 kilometers is nothing you
see is nothing is is very less let's say
the range distance from Mumbai for
example to let's say
Beijing it's 4.7 th000 kilometers so
even if the AG missile has a
range of 5,000 kilometers we essentially
cover the whole of China in that let's
see the distance from Gujarat to let's
say U um let's say
London it's 7,000 kilm so if the Agy 5
has a 8,000 kilometer range then it can
cover the whole of Europe so
yeah so the Chinese are claiming this
why would they claim this they probably
want to make it look like it's not aimed
for China but it's aimed for the West
possibly but you know what people are
not kids especially in the world of
international relations geopolitics the
whole world understands who India's
number one adversary is who India's
number one threat is and that is not
Pakistan it is China and any long range
missile would be developed with China in
mind so yeah they will make all kinds of
claims and all that which they should
they we have to play the game right but
it's essentially developed with China in
mind if as long as it's you know 6 7
8,000 kilm range obviously it should
also have other countries in
its in its umbrella why not because why
not so
yeah okay the UK research group predicts
the second India China war will occur
between 2025 and 2030 what's my
perspective do I do I think it's
feasible so India and China first went
to war for the first time in their
history in
1962 that the first war the second was a
limit War 1967 India lost the 62 War
India won the 67 war and there was a
significant clash in the late 80s also I
think it was in
87 so if you take 67 in 87 to be limited
Wars like kill kgil was a limited War as
we know then India and China have gone
to war thce but let's say okay that
that's all part of History fine so some
research group in the U UK has
apparently predicted that the second
India China war will occur between 2025
and 2030 what's my
perspective uh well it all depends on
various factors do I think it will
happen I think it is
actually it's it's not unlikely entirely
unlikely but it would be fool hearty for
Any Nation any of the two Nations either
India or China to go to war with the
other because what do you achieve you're
going to achieve nothing look the
terrain the terrain between that that
demarcates the India border which is the
current India China border is extremely
inhospitable extremely mountainous the
highest mountainous range in the
world extremely high altitudes you go
there and just you're going to have
trouble breathing just standing you if
somebody asks you to run it's going to
be next to impossible for you to run for
more than five minutes okay that's how
high the altitude is That's How Low the
amount of oxygen in the the air is over
here so it's almost possible it is it is
definitely impossible to have tank
warfare to have
uh um you know mechanized charges all
that and when it comes to fighter planes
and all that Tibet is at such a high
altitude that fighter planes have to
take off with a lower payload let's say
you have a fighter plane that has a
payload of let's say 5,000 kilograms
just
hypothetically well the amount of
payload you can take off with depends on
your altitude
because your fuel needs to combust with
oxygen to produce thrust okay in the jet
engine if you're taking off from sea
level you have extremely dense
saturation of oxygen in the atmosphere
in the air which means your jet engine
will perform at the highest if you're
taking off from C Level but if you're
taking off from let's say 5,000 kilm
above C Level you're going to have a lot
less oxygen in the air which means your
fighter plane will not be able to take
off with a payload of 5,000 kilg of
weapons but maybe only 2,000 kgs of
weapons which is a huge problem when it
comes to India our airfields are south
of the Himalayas so we can take off from
much lower altitudes which means our
fighter planes can take off with much
heavier payloads when it comes to China
their fighter planes can take off with
lower payloads lighter payloads and all
the posss are exposed because there is
no Forest cover up
there and then whatever fighting will
happen it will have to be mantoan
fighting because of the extremely
inhospitable terrain and then please
let's not forget that both Nations have
nuclear weapons and God forbid if
certain red lines are crossed you you
don't want a nuclear exchange so you may
be China that's that's the second
largest economy in the world and you've
spent so many decades building up this
economy and you make one stupid mistake
and you lose everything so do you want
to be in that situation if you are China
in that position if you're China so
because of all these things I think it's
unlikely that the two Nations will have
any significant Clash of course I could
be wrong if some idiot somewhere makes a
stupid Choice then who knows what could
happen so I don't think there's any
idiot in power either in India or China
definitely not Mr Shi Jinping is not a
crazy person Mr Modi obviously we know
he's a very very capable leader so is Mr
shining actually so I don't think any
stupid thing will happen unless some
crazy military commander does something
stupid so I think that if a war does
happen which it may it could be a
localized limited war going Beyond a
localized War would be extremely
dangerous for both
Nations so yeah that's how I see
it all right what else do we
have Ram panjwani says can India and
China relations
improve in the future India and China's
relations can improve in the future only
when first of all India Rises to a to a
to an amount of hard power that is
comparable to that of China and secondly
when the Tibet issue is resolved as long
as India and China two massively
powerful Nations and massively large
Nations have a common border there's
always going to be the adversarial
relationship you simply cannot have a
good relationship when two powerful and
large Nations share a common border
okay so for India and China to be peace
have a peaceful relationship again like
we have always had we need Tibet to be
independent again and that
obviously will take time so in the
future what's the earliest that Tibet
could be free maybe
2050 or something like that I don't know
it depends on so many different factors
that you cannot you know make a
prediction there are some people who
love making predictions I don't so I'm
I'm saying maybe by 2050 you may have a
change so if Tibet becomes independent
again then India and China could have
good relations you know one of the major
factors that that kind of
uh is is that contributes to reasonably
okay relations between Russia and China
is the fact that Mongolia exists as a
large buffer state of course half of
Mongolia has been taken over by China
it's called inner Mongolia which has
been occupied and annexed by China just
the way same way they have taken
Tibet but this large Nation Mongolia
which is mostly empty which is a very
small population it acts as a buffer
between Russia and China which is why
the the kind of border that Russia and
China have is is much smaller than what
what it otherwise would have been and
that contributes to some kind of
stability between in the relations
between the two Nations if this entire
bard order was just Russia and China the
two nations would not be able to live in
peace
together so what we need is Tibet to be
free again in that case India and
China's relations could will definitely
improve in the
future
okay okay so refreshing spot says in
today's multi-polar world is India
getting closer to Russia China side no
India is playing its own role in
geopolitics India is essentially playing
the role of a bridge between uh the
global South and the Western Nations the
Western nations are the Nations that are
led by the US controlled by the US which
is the nations of the EU of NATO and all
the other nations in in the Americas all
that and so that's the West the global
South is the other nations the nations
of Africa and uh the nations of Asia Etc
so India is kind of a bridge between
these two and you know even Russia is
now is considered to be an Asian Nation
because the West doesn't want to
consider Russia to be a western Nation
so India is playing its own game okay
India doesn't want to take sides India
wants to have good relations with
everybody India wants to trade with
everybody we
want uh we want Russian Russian oil we
want Western technology and we will pay
for it obviously we not stealing
anything so that's the kind of
constructive role India wants to play
and India obviously aspires to rise
again become a major Power by 2047 2050
which we should so we not taking sides
we want to
be in good on good terms with everybody
so India is not getting closer to the
Russia China side China it's there's no
chance of India getting closer to China
because the Chinese are so belligerent
and we have this huge border dispute and
the Chinese refus to demarcate the the
border and this actually plays into
Russia's hands because Russia is also
afraid of getting too close to China and
becoming too dependent on China so
there's this weird triangle triangular
game happening between India Russia
China where the rise of India is is it
actually makes Russia's life easier
because it puts pressure on China so
that's the deal uh that's how it
is all right what else do we have
okay Karthik says I sometimes fail to
understand why India underestimates
Mongolia I mean don't you think we must
develop significant relationships with
Mongolia so that we can have more
military bases on the
land
um let's take a look at Mongolia what's
the population of
Mongolia let me check the population of
Mongolia
what's the population of Mongolia 33
lakhs which is 3.3 million I am pretty
sure that most cities in India will be
larger than this okay so the population
is insignificant the land area is is big
but Mongolia is a nation that doesn't
have any real power it doesn't have a
significant military it has no
significant economy it is trapped
between two giant Powers it's
essentially it only serves one purpose
that of a buffer State between Russia
and China and that's the only reason why
it has been allowed to remain
independent otherwise the Chinese or the
or the Russians would have gobbled it up
long
ago okay yes Mongolia used to be very
powerful during the time of Shar chingis
Khan those days are long gone those days
are long gone it's a I I I I am very
fond of Mongolia I would love to see
Mongolia rise again and and become
prosperous again but today it is not in
that s of the Jewish it is a big
territory but there is nothing to
underestimate or overestimate over here
you have to be realistic as to
understanding each nation's position in
the global World Order and Mongolia is
today a nation that is to be very
realistic a nation that doesn't have
much power doesn't have a significant
economy doesn't have significant
population the only plus point the only
thing that is in their favor is that
they are independent still and they have
a large amount of territory that's all
and you can't simply have military bases
in Mongolia the Chinese won allow that
the Russians won't allow that how do you
resupply those bases think
logically think logically you have to
supply military bases you have to have
lines of communication look at the map
to to supply your your hypothetical
military bases in Mongolia you would
have to fly over China you think China
will allow those or flights think
logically even the Russians won't allow
that they they they consider Mongolia to
be part of their zone of influence if
you if you know history you will know
why so you have to be realistic in when
when you think about these things we we
not playing children's games here there
are so many factors that you have to
consider and it is simply unsustainable
un unfeasible to to have Indian military
bases in
Mongolia all right what
else um
okay
says we so my friend Jay is saying that
he's from Quebec and he confirms what
I'm saying about the truth of the
society over there in Quebec in Canada
right now there's this big debate about
transexuals and all that so that is the
big
big struggle societal struggle that the
West is facing transsexuals and and
lgbtq and all that these are the big
challenges and the big Quest For Justice
in the
west you have to uplift the
people you know you cannot take these
Fringe things and make them mainstream
of course you can do whatever you want
but
uh yeah so so what Jay is essentially
saying is that there is this big debate
right now in Canada in Quebec about the
transexuals and Mr Mr Justin tudo is one
of the biggest champions of this you
know the the rainbow flag I look I have
nothing against anybody of any sexuality
who cares who cares what someone
sexuality is what what matters is what
you do with your life what you
contribute to to society that's what
matters who cares what you do in the
privacy of your house nobody cares but
that's what they want to to make the
whole world about today you know the the
woke uh rulers of rulers of the
West so you know and and that's what's
taught in schools to children they
taught about I don't know gay sex or
whatever I that's what I hear which is
terrible children should be taught
should be given the tools that equip
them to succeed in life and what's
success in life it's it's to rise to the
fullest extent of your potential
everybody has a certain amount of
potential in them everybody has some
talance and the purpose of life is is to
contribute to society that's my opinion
you may disagree with that if you the
when the time comes to depart from this
world on your last day if you look back
at your life and you find that you have
given more to society than you've taken
from from society then I think you had a
good you lived a good life that's how I
see the that's how I see things so
that's what you should equip people to
do to succeed at that in contributing
something good to society contributing
genuine value to society who cares what
your sexuality is or what your gender is
or what your gender range is so what
essentially being done to Western
Society is they are destroying Western
Society they're tearing down the the the
the moral fabric of
society they are they are not
inculcating children and young people
with any
you know any set of values or any any
set of
Standards it's it's about lowering the
standards of society that's what's
happening it's it's so unfortunate I
mean you know yeah I would like to see
everyone happy but all over the world
white black green pink North American
European Asian African everybody
but yeah that's just the way it is right
now okay subramanyam J Shankar Namaste
sir saying in a War or conflict will
Russia support India or Pakistan
hypothetically Russia in a hypothetical
war between India and Pakistan will say
that will will be neutral Russia will be
neutral Russia will Russia obviously
knows who's going to win so they will
not antagonize India by by doing
anything stupid or saying anything
stupid but they will give out the
general statement that please stop
fighting please resolve your disputes
through negotiations all the standard
diplomatic talk that anybody would do I
mean if if uh when when Russia and the
Ukraine thing happened India said the
same things that this is not a time for
war please go to the negotiating table
and resolve your de differences through
negotiations that's the standard
statement that any responsible Nation
would make so if India and Pakistan go
to war Russia will
say same thing of course after half an
hour there will be no need to say the
same thing because the war will be will
be over but there you have it
there you have it I'm being realistic
here Cricket tug off Nations do you
think dropping Virat kohy in T20 World
Cup will do any good to India BCC says
they need power pack players I think vat
kohi will do best in pressure situations
you know you have to keep changing you
have to keep evolving when the
Australians dropped Steve War there was
this big outcry but the team kept on
doing well they dropped Dean Jones in
the late 80s for no reason when he was
at the peak of his form at the peak you
know in the prime of his of his career
and they just dropped him and they never
took him again but they kept doing well
you have to be ruthless you have to be
ruthless I'm not saying that Ki should
be dropped I'm not opining any such
thing but in case it is that's what they
do I think they probably know what
they're doing I'm sure Ki is is is at a
certain age where it may be time to
start thinking about a post Cricket life
possibly he's not the youngest guy in
more I'm sure he must be in his 30s um
you know 35 is old for a sports person
unless you had Jimmy Anderson who in his
who must be like 58 years old by now
Jimmy Anderson the swing bowler English
English swing bowler must be at least 58
by now but typically 35 is kind of when
you would want to move on not sure how
old 35 36 37 the great man Ashwin is
still going strong he must be 35 or 36
so
on uh so when it comes to T20 you need
to be really
to be really strong vat isn't the
biggest and strongest guy I he's very
fit obviously we know one of the fittest
guys around so I think you know we are a
nation of 1.4 billion people there is so
much talent you think there are not 700
people who are more talented than kie
out there of course there
are so it's about the nation first the
cause first we want to win we don't want
a repeat of the of the World Cup the 50
over World Cup in which certain you know
what happened yeah we did extremely well
until the final so yeah so I think it's
okay if they decide to drop Ki I mean
theyve they've dropped Ashwin so many
times that guy would have had 600 test
wickets by now if he had not been
dropped so many times he's he's probably
the best spinner in the world right now
and they keep dropping him so if they
can drop Ashwin then the same thing the
same kind of thing could happen to GOI
as well I have nothing against it I'm
always in in favor of rapid change and
always get the best young people in
always get the best young people in I'm
sure there are people who have served
the nation for so many years and they've
made so many runs and all but you know
what when there are younger people
bitter people stronger people out there
hungrier people out there who don't earn
millions of dollars a year but who want
to do that give them a chance so that's
how I see it my
friends ging lover says why is Indian
style architecture traditional
architecture not reflected in new modern
buildings government government
buildings Etc in India I mean go to
Japan they prioritize their architecture
they showcase their architecture
government buildings are built with
Japanese style architecture go to China
you will see Chinese style architecture
go to go to uh nations in the in the in
the Middle East the Arabian Peninsula
Etc you will see government buildings
Etc built using Arabic style
architecture and so on but India has the
ugliest government buildings in the
world which have no style whatsoever
just rectangles and boxes it's because
of because there is no sense of
Pride the you know what there are lots
of really good bureaucrats in India
today young hungry bureaucrats want to
serve the nation okay so of late I am
seeing really really good people coming
in and I'm sure in you know there are
many senior bureaucrats also who are
really good but I would say if you take
the average
bureaucrat okay that person is typically
deracinated they go through the upsc
syllabus which totally exposes them to
all the wrong ideas anti-india
hinduphobic ideas so they you you study
that for two three years to pass the
upsc exam you're going to be crammed
your brain is going to be crammed full
of all these thoughts these Notions that
essentially terms India as an inferior
culture all the whatever you study in
history for upsc is the ncrt nonsense
and all that you know the British were
great reformers they came to to to
uplift India from poverty H and the
mughals were the best thing that
happened to India and Indian culture is
inferior all that nonsense you go
through that for a few years you're
going to have no pride in Indian culture
and you will want want
to you know uh have buildings that are
ugly
have nothing to do with Indian
Styles uh and of course there is the
cost cutting that happens and schimming
sometimes that allegedly happens it is
said and so on so obviously you would
have the you would want to have
buildings that have no style at all with
the least amount of cost
possible and that's what you see so that
is why it is so once you bring in the
sense of pride in identity and
civilizational identity then you will
have different you will see something
else in
India ADI says upsc has such syllabus I
I'll tell you something even a person
who who is proud to be Indian you make
them study that syllabus for two or
three years to pass the exam they'll
become leftists they they'll start
hating India they'll start you know
having strong doubts about Indian
culture
they'll start believing that we used to
burn our women
alive that Sati used to happen in every
every corner of every city and every
village they they'll they'll believe
that we were the most inegalitarian
misogynistic patriarchal oppressive
Society in human
history you go through that syllabus and
you study that you to cram that over and
over again you do that for one or two
years you're going to be you going to
emerge at completely different person so
yes that is the case
that is the
case push tiwari says is Modi a good PM
because somebody always allgates
him listen why do you care about
people's opinions about what x person or
Y person says about Prime Minister Modi
why don't you see where India was in
2014 when Mr Modi became prime minister
and where do you see where India is
today how do you quantify the change
look at where India's GDP is look at the
number of airports India has look at how
much ra Railways have or have not been
built look at how many highways have or
have not been built look at how many
people have been brought into the
banking system how many people have bank
accounts look at how many people you
know how many new gas connections have
have been given how many new water
connections have been given look at the
infrastructure that's been built and
look at how it was in the 10 years
before Mr Modi came to power so that you
can compare this 10 year period with
this 10 year period and then you can see
for yourself what what the truth is how
do you care what someone says I just
don't understand why you need to look
into people's opinion
don't listen to anyone's opinions
including mine look at what cannot be
denied
numbers but obviously it takes some work
to do it and people are lazy no no no I
don't want have the time I don't know
where to look it is too difficult to do
the research myself it will take you
five minutes but you will not do
it please raise your standards learn how
to seek out the truth so that you don't
have to depend on anyone's
opinion I also have opinions so so and
so YouTuber also will have opinions
everybody has an opinion just like
everybody has a nose so you need to stay
out of everybody's nose and you need to
look at the actual hard num statistics
data learn how to seek this out it's all
available for free on the
internet then you will not have to ask
me or YouTuber X or YouTuber y as to
what the truth is because you will see
the truth for
yourself so that's my message to all of
you all of you please learn how to
do research on the internet and learn
how to differentiate facts from
opinions facts are just numbers just
numbers a number is a number an opinion
is a story do you understand the
difference between a
story and a number or a set of numbers
always rely on hard data numbers cannot
be falsified you cannot imagine numbers
or invent numbers numbers are reported
numbers right so that's what I would say
to you I don't care what so and so
YouTuber says or doesn't say about the
Prime
Minister okay the the track record of
the prime minister speaks for itself in
my opinion he's the best prime minister
we've had since 1947 and now some people
will say I'm a bck or this or that I
don't care doesn't make any difference
to me doesn't make any difference to me
whatsoever so that's how I see it please
verify that for yourself sir
Gil chandarana says I am F fully
connected to my Dharma but I had to give
upsc because of my parents
wishes yeah well that's life you know
you got to please people you got to
please parents you go to please family
you you have all these requirements that
are you know you have to fulfill as as a
as a member of a family as a member of
society sometimes you have to put other
people's wishes in front of yours ahead
of yours
uh and sometimes you should know what is
best for you and sometimes you have to
look at the end of the day nobody will
remember what sacrifices you made to
make one or two people happy at the end
of the
day you will be you will be judged Bas
on based on what you contributed to
society let's say you could have been a
great entrepreneur but
you you know just to make someone happy
let's say your your mom or your dad
happy you did upsc and you became a
bureaucrat and you spend your entire
life carrying out people's orders did
you contribute to society the way you
could have contributed as a great
entrepreneur maybe you did not probably
you did not so at the end of the day you
know what really matters is what you do
in your life and what you give back to
the world and sometimes you may have to
displease people but as long as you do
it for the right cause for the right
reasons then
I think it would be justified you know
uh so yeah so you are saying that you
are fully connected to your Dharma but
you have to give upsc you to go through
the upsc you know study process and take
the exams set for the exam well then I
I'm pretty sure you know what I mean
when I say that you know that syllabus
will make you doubt your own culture
your own your own history and all that
so I hope you went through you know were
not too too badly affected by that
uh my history teacher keeps telling us
that we Indians were tribals primitive
rag tag tribals and the British came and
modernized us and uplifted us but when I
argued her on this fact on this fact I
was in insulted in front of the class
but why I'll tell you why because your
teacher is a godamn idiot she's a
that's why I'll tell you what please
understand something see you know you
know we Indians we are taught that our
teachers are our gurus and we must
always have the utmost respect for them
do you so so to that I would say this do
you know the true meaning of the of of
the term
Guru a guru is not someone who will
charge you a fee every
month and a guru will not stop teaching
you if you are no longer able to pay
that fee a guru is your teacher for life
okay and the guru will not give you will
will not say that if you pay me six
months at a single go I will give you
30% % discount so a teacher is not a
guru a teacher is a service provider a
teacher doesn't care about you a teacher
has hundreds of students and you just a
number for that for that person okay so
stop putting teachers on a pedestal some
teachers a very few of them are genuine
gems and if you have such such a teacher
you are one of the luckiest people in
the world a genuinely good teacher but
most teachers are mediocre most teachers
have no knowledge whatsoever they will
simply take what's in textbook and
regurgitate you and they hate students
asking questions and when a student asks
questions that student is labeled as a
troublemaker and then they they will
insult you because they have this
position of power so my advice to those
of you who are in school and college and
all that is this there's no need to
argue with idiots okay whatever
knowledge you can gain if any at all
from your these so-called teachers you
gain it I personally have gained no
knowledge ever in classrooms whatever
knowledge I have gained in my life is
through my own self-study outside of
classrooms classrooms are a waste of
time you you learn nothing just like
podcasts essentially you learn nothing
you may get ideas and you may get
direction from podcasts but you will get
no real knowledge unless you sit down
and study and read from a book you will
get some tidbits of Knowledge from
podcasts and you may get inspiration
from podcast to study but the real
knowledge comes from self study only
from sitting down alone with a book and
spending a few hours reading so my point
is don't argue with idiots many teachers
are idiots some teachers are genuinely
good people if you have such such a
teacher you are lucky you should cherish
the teacher teacher but most of them are
idiots I say this from personal
experience most but I've had I've been
lucky enough to have one or two good
teachers you know but most of them are
abysmally poor in terms of Standards so
don't argue with idiots all i'
say all right let's take one more
question 2 hours 10 minutes long long
time we've done this uh let's take one
more question let's take one more
question um um um there so many
questions what shall I
take
um uh let us see
okay okay let's we didn't talk about
Russia Ukraine today did we okay ATA
says what's the current situation of
Russia Ukraine war and what will be the
next step of Putin as he will as it is
be a selected President of Russia okay
so we have the Russian presidential
elections this year I wonder who will
win will Mr Putin win I assure you he
will win as he should uh so look Mr
Putin is going to win the elections we
know that okay I'm not making fun of the
system over there or the process over
there or of Mr Putin he is the Right
leader for Russia right now and he
should keep on ruling from the Russian
national interest perspective so his is
going to win the elections we know
that so what's the next step look this
is a long process this war is just the
beginning of a complete reconfiguration
of the global geopolitical World Order
and eventually the way I see it look
Ukraine essentially has been destroyed
they
have thrown all of their young men into
the jaws of war the horrible the term
they use the meat grinder the young men
are gone now they're throwing old men
into the me grender and pregnant women
also pregnant women are fighting the
battle battles now so Ukraine has been
finished as a as a nation as a society
okay and at some point in time Russia
will decide what happens with with
Ukraine so most likely Ukraine will be
partitioned some part of it could go to
Poland and a lot of it could go to
Russia and some part of it could remain
as a rump State that's how I see it so U
and the West has failed in defeating
Russia or or harming Russia the
sanctions have backfired they have done
more harm to Europe than to Russia so
that's the situation right
now and time will tell how long this war
will last maybe it will be over in the
next six months maybe it will last
another three years five years who knows
but it's the it's it's the beginning of
a larger conflict the total
reconfiguration of the geopolitical
world order and the era of multipolarity
that we are in right now right so that's
that's how I see it right now all right
uh ladies gentlemen everybody am I
excited for the Mike Tyson fight yes I
am I would like to see Mike Iron Mike
fight again he's going to fight one of
the pool Brothers is it Jake or the
other one whoever it is but yeah I would
love to see him fight one more time left
hook in the peekaboo style love it yeah
so let's see that all right everybody
thank you so much for all the questions
I apologize to those of you whose
questions I have not been able to take
obviously there have been so many
questions and I've only been able to
take a few but I'm going to make this um
a more regular thing now of of late I
have done very few ask abijit episodes
but I'm going to make it much more
regular now so I look forward to seeing
you next Saturday same time same channel
and I'll take many more of your
questions at that time thank you so much
for watching thank you thank you so much
take care and keep raising your
standards until next time bye-bye